{"tossups": [{"question": "This state\u2019s Pingree Associates established America\u2019s largest conservation easement around its Allagash River in 2001. This state\u2019s eastern boundary is partially formed by the St. Croix River, which was surveyed as part of Jay\u2019s Treaty. One country hid the Mitchell Map during a dispute over this state\u2019s northern border, which was established along the St. John\u2019s River. The Aroostook War was fought between New Brunswick and, for ten points, what state with capital Augusta?", "answer": "<b> Maine</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "One supporter of these people launched the failed Atterbury Plot. An uprising of these people is the subject of the song \u201cJohnny Cope.\u201d These people launched the failed \u201cForty-Five\u201d uprising which was defeated at the Battle of Culloden. These people believed in the legitimacy of Bonnie Prince Charlie to the throne. For ten points, name these people who claimed that the House of Stuart were the legitimate heirs to the British throne.", "answer": "<b> Jacobite</b>s", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This work ends by saying \u201cinstead of gazing at each other with suspicious or doubtful curiosity, let each of us hold out [...] the hearty hand of friendship,\u201d before calling \u201cLet the names of Whig and Tory be extinct.\u201d Benajmin Rush edited this work, whose final section calculates the value of the British navy, noting America\u2019s natural resources give it the potential to rival it. The absurdity of an island ruling over a continent is noted by, for ten points, what 1776 pro-revolution pamphlet by Thomas Paine?", "answer": "<b> Common Sense</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "War broke out between this country and its eastern neighbour after the death of Inspector Grosgurin. Guy Tachard was sent by Louis XIV to become ambassador of this modern day country. This non-European country underwent a 1688 revolution, which overthrew the pro-foreign King Narai. This modern day country, once home to the Ayutthaya Kingdom, is now led by the Chakri Dynasty\u2019s King Rama IX. For ten points, name this country formerly known as Siam, whose capital is Bangkok.", "answer": "<b> Thailand</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The twelve Jyotirlinga [j\u2019yoh-teer-LINGA] shrines dedicated to this god include one at Somnath and the Rameswaram temple, which includes a body of water named for Agni, a cognate of this modern god. Statues of this god wear five serpents and hold a trident in one of their four arms. With Parvati, this god is the father of Ganesha. For ten points, name this Hindu destruction god who forms the Trimurti with Brahma and Vishnu.", "answer": "<b> Shiva</b> (or<b> Siva</b>)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s crew was saved from scurvy by treebark tea, a solution provided by Domagaya from the Stadacona village; The next spring, he kidnapped Domagaya and Donnacona to bring back to Europe. This man names a bridge that reaches Saint Helen\u2019s Island as it connects Longueuil [long-ay] and Montreal Island. This man\u2019s failure to find a Northwest Passage resulted in claims on the Saint Lawrence River. For ten points, name this explorer who, in the 1530s, claimed Canada for France.", "answer": "Jacques<b> Cartier</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "He disappeared on a rescue mission in 1928.", "answer": "Roald<b> Amundsen</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "One politician from this country, Robert Grimm, attempted to negotiate peace between Germany and Russia, causing an affair that led to the resignation of this country\u2019s councilor Arthur Hoffmann. This country\u2019s actions during World War II were the subject of the Bergier Commission. Jean-Henri Durant was so shocked at the devastation from the Battle of Solferino that he founded the Red Cross in this country, which is divided into 26 cantons. For ten points, name this neutral country in the Alps whose cities include Zurich and Geneva.", "answer": "<b> Switzerland</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "New Zealand was the first country to legalize this action in 1893.", "answer": "<b> women\u2019s suffrage</b> (accept descriptions of allowing<b> women</b> to<b> vote</b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "This man hosted a fundraiser for the Black Panthers that Tom Wolfe described as \u201cradical chic.\u201d His third symphony was dedicated to the memory of JFK and was based on the Jewish prayer for the dead. Another piece by this composer of the<em> Kaddish</em> Symphony included a \u201crumble\u201d between the Sharks and Jets and songs such as \u201cGee, Officer Krupke\u201d and \u201cAmerica\u201d. For ten points, what conductor of the New York Philharmonic wrote the music for<em> West Side Story</em>?", "answer": "Leonard<b> Bernstein</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "Pope Alexander II sent papal standards to the victor of this battle in an attempt to expand Catholic power. Many retreating troops from the losing side of this battle fell into the Evil Ditch, or the \u201cMalfosse.\u201dIn this battle, which was preceded by an engagement at Fulford, the losing side\u2019s huscarls could not prevent their king from being shot in the eye. The English formed a shield wall in this battle, fought three weeks after Harald Hardrada was killed at Stamford Bridge. For ten points, name this 1066 victory for William the Conqueror over Harold Godwinson.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Hastings</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "After this man gave up alcohol, he allegedly received divine aid in his fight against Rana Sanga. In his early career, this man saw his rival Mohammed Shaybani Khan capture Ferghana and Samarkand from him, though he was able to seize Kabul. Alam Khan and Dawlat Khan encouraged this descendant of Genghis Khan to launch one invasion that culminated in the defeat of Ibrahim Lodi at the battle of Panipat. For ten points, name this father of Humayun and founder of the Mughal Dynasty.", "answer": "<b> Babur</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>In 1919, socialist Victor Berger\u2019s seat in Congress was disqualified under this amendment\u2019s third section. John Bingham reworded one section of this amendment to</b> <b>remove language describing (+)</b> <b>racial discrimination in favor of broader protection.</b> <b>Its</b> <b>fourth section refused to honor debts made by the Confederacy, and its first section notes that \u201c[no] State shall deprive any person of life, liberty, or property without (*)</b> due process of law.\u201d The Equal Protection clause is contained in, for ten points, what Reconstruction amendment that granted \u201call persons born [...] in the United States\u201d citizenship?", "answer": "<b> 14</b>th Amendment", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This song\u2019s final line was sometimes changed in performance to say that Jimmy Carter\u2019s\u201cgot the answer.\u201d This song references the Swampers of Muscle Shoals, and features the line \u201cNow Watergate does not bother me, does your conscience bother you?\u201d Written as a response to Neil Young\u2019s (+) \u201cSouthern Man,\u201d its writer claimed that the line \u201cBoo! Boo! Boo!\u201d meant that he did not actually love Governor (*)</b> George Wallace. For ten points, name this Lynyrd Skynyrd song about a Southern state \u201cwhere the skies are so blue.\u201d", "answer": "<b> Sweet Home Alabama</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Operation Fortitude North gave the impression that an invasion of this country was imminent. Ahmed Bouchiki was killed in this country by Mossad agents who thought he</b> <b>was a member of Black September. (+)</b> <b>Oscar II renounced his claim to the throne of this</b> <b>country, leading to Haakon VII becoming king. This country was ruled by the Nasjonal (*) </b>Samling party during its occupation by Nazi Germany under Prime Minister Vidkun Quisling. For ten points, name this Scandinavian country whose capital is Oslo.", "answer": "<b> Norway</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Lanoe Hawker, the</b> <b>so-called \u201cBritish Boelcke,\u201d was killed by this instigator of \u201cBloody April,\u201d whose pursuit of a Sopwith Camel ended with his defeat near (*) </b> Amiens [ah-mee-ehn] in April 1918 by Roy Brown. For ten points, name this leader of the Flying Circus, a distinguished German ace of World War I.", "answer": "The<b> Red Baron</b> (or Manfred von<b> Richthofen</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>In 1765, protesters met at the corner of Essex and Orange Streets in this city to hang an effigy of Andrew Oliver, a proponent of the Stamp Act, in a tree; ten years later, the occupying British cut that tree down to a \u201cLiberty Stump.\u201d The phrase</b> <b>\u201cthis (+)</b> <b>meeting can do nothing more to save the country\u201d was spoken by John</b> <b>meeting can do nothing more to save the country\u201d was spoken by John</b> <b>Adams in this city, apocryphally serving as code to the crowd to put on (*)</b> <b>Adams in this city, apocryphally serving as code to the crowd to put on (*)</b> Native American disguises and boarding the<em> Dartmouth</em>,<em> Eleanor</em>, and<em> Beaver</em> in this city\u2019s harbor. For ten points, name this Massachusetts city, the site of a 1773 Tea Party.", "answer": "<b> Boston</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}